<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Mumbai Tour Guide</string>

    <string name="architecture">Architecture</string>
    <string name="museum">Museum</string>
    <string name="restaurants">Restaurants</string>
    <string name="events">Events</string>

    <!--Architecture -->
    <string name="gateway">GATEWAY OF INDIA</string>
    <string name="gateway_desc">The Gateway of India is an arch monument built during the 20th century in Bombay, India. The monument was erected to commemorate the landing of King George V and Queen Mary at Apollo Bunder on their visit to India in 1911. The structural plan of Gateway of India is designed in the Indo-Saracenic style.</string>

    <string name="elephanta">ELEPHANTA</string>
    <string name="elephanta_desc">Elephanta Caves are a UNESCO World Heritage Site and a collection of cave temples predominantly dedicated to Hindu god Shiva. They are located on Elephanta Island, or Gharapuri (literally "the city of caves") in Mumbai Harbour, 10 kilometres (6.2 mi) to the east of the city of Mumbai in the Indian state of Mahārāshtra. The island, located offshore about 2 kilometres (1.2 mi) west of the Jawaharlal Nehru Port, consists of Shaivism caves and a few Buddhist stupa mounds.A Persian inscription suggest that it was ransacked during Sultunate/muslim period.\nThe Elephanta Caves contain rock cut stone sculptures, that show syncretism of Hindu and Buddhist ideas and iconography. The caves are hewn from solid basalt rock. Except for a few exceptions, much of the artwork is defaced and damaged. The main temple\'s orientation as well as the relative location of other temples are placed in a mandala pattern. The carvings narrate Hindu mythologies, with the large monolithic 20 feet (6.1 m) Trimurti Sadashiva (three-faced Shiva), Nataraja (Lord of dance) and Yogishvara (Lord of Yoga) being the most celebrated.\nThe origins and date when the caves were constructed have attracted considerable speculations and scholarly attention since the 19th century. These date them between 5th and 9th century, and attribute them to various Hindu dynasties. They are more commonly placed between 5th and 7th centuries. Most scholars consider it to have been completed by about 550 CE.\nThey were named Elefante – which morphed to Elephanta – by the colonial Portuguese when they found elephant statues on it. They established a base on the island, and its soldiers damaged the sculpture and caves. The main cave (Cave 1, or the Great Cave) was a Hindu place of worship until the Portuguese arrived, whereupon the island ceased to be an active place of worship. The earliest attempts to prevent further damage to the Caves were started by British India officials in 1909. The monuments were restored in the 1970s. In 1987, the restored Elephanta Caves were designated a UNESCO World Heritage Site. It is currently maintained by the Archaeological Survey of India (ASI).</string>

    <string name="haji">HAJI ALI DARGAH</string>
    <string name="haji_desc">The Haji Ali Dargah is a mosque and dargah (tomb) located on an islet off the coast of Worli in the southern part of Mumbai. Near the heart of the city proper, the dargah is one of the most recognisable landmarks of Mumbai. An exquisite example of Indo-Islamic Architecture, associated with legends about doomed lovers, the dargah contains the tomb of Sayed Peer Haji Ali Shah Bukhari</string>

    <string name="bwsl">BANDRA-WORLI SEA LINK</string>
    <string name="bwsl_desc">The Bandra–Worli Sea Link is a cable-stayed bridge with pre-stressed concrete-steel viaducts on either side that links Bandra in the Western Suburbs of Mumbai with Worli in South Mumbai. The bridge is a part of the proposed Western Freeway that will link the Western Suburbs to Nariman Point in Mumbai\'s main business district.\nThe ₹16 billion (US$250 million) bridge was commissioned by the Maharashtra State Road Development Corporation(MSRDC), and built by the Hindustan Construction Company. The first four of the eight lanes of the bridge were opened to the public on 30 June 2009. All eight lanes were opened on 24 March 2010.\nThe sea-link reduces travel time between Bandra and Worli during peak hours from 60–90 minutes to 20–30 minutes. As of October 2009, BWSL had an average daily traffic of around 37,500 vehicles.</string>

    <!-- Museum -->
    <string name="csmvs">Chhatrapati Shivaji Maharaj Vastu Sangrahalaya</string>
    <string name="csmvs_desc">The Chhatrapati Shivaji Maharaj Vastu Sangrahalaya (translation: \'king Shivaji museum\'), abbreviated CSMVS and formerly named the Prince of Wales Museum of Western India, is the main museum in Mumbai, Maharashtra. It was founded in the early years of the 20th century by prominent citizens of Mumbai, with the help of the government, to commemorate the visit of Edward VIII, who was Prince of Wales at the time. It is located in the heart of South Mumbai near the Gateway of India. The museum was renamed in the 1990s or early 2000s after Shivaji, the founder of Maratha Empire. Prior to this, Dr. Bhau Daji Lad Museum, formerly the Victoria and Albert Museum, was established in 1855, just opposite Byculla railway station, Mumbai.\nThis museum is located inside the Victoria Garden, now called Jijamata Udyaan. This Gothic architecture building was revived a few years ago by the Mumbai municipal corporation authorities.The building is built in the Indo-Saracenic style of architecture, incorporating elements of other styles of architecture like the Mughal, Maratha and Jain. The museum building is surrounded by a garden of palm trees and formal flower beds.\nThe museum houses approximately 50,000 exhibits of ancient Indian history as well as objects from foreign lands, categorized primarily into three sections: Art, Archaeology and Natural History. The museum houses Indus Valley Civilization artefacts, and other relics from ancient India from the time of the Guptas, Mauryas, Chalukyas and Rashtrakuta.</string>

    <string name="nsc">NEHRU SCIENCE CENTRE</string>
    <string name="nsc_desc">Nehru Science Center (NSC) is the largest interactive science centre in India. It is located in Worli, Mumbai. The centre is named after India\'s first Prime Minister, Jawaharlal Nehru. In 1977, the centre started with the \'Light and Sight\' exhibition, and then in 1979 a Science Park was built. On 11 November 1985 it was opened to the public by Rajiv Gandhi, the then Prime Minister of India.\nIn 1977, Nehru Science Centre, first conceived as a Science and Technology Museum in late sixties, took final shape as India\'s largest interactive science centre, to match the world trends in such public institutions. The centre opened its first semi-permanent exhibition `Light and Sight\' in 1977 followed by the world\'s first ever Science Park in 1979, during the International Year of the child. On 11 November 1985 the full-fledged science centre was finally opened to public by the late Rajiv Gandhi, then Prime Minister of India.\nNehru Science Centre, the largest Science Centre in the country has a sprawling 8 acres (32,000 m2) of science park with varieties of plants, trees and shrubs. More than 500 hands-on and interactive science exhibits on energy, sound, kinematics, mechanics, transport, etc. are installed in the park. The NSC building, with its unique architecture, houses several permanent science expositions on various theme.\nNational Council of Science Museums (NCSM), the parent body of Nehru Science Centre, Mumbai, with its 25 science centres / museums all over the country, has the best infrastructure and skilled manpower to conceptualise, design, develop and organise high quality science exhibits and other related educational programmes and activities.</string>

    <string name="jag">JEHANGIR ART GALLERY</string>
    <string name="jag_desc">The Jehangir Art Gallery is an art gallery in Mumbai (India). It was founded by Sir Cowasji Jehangir at the urging of K. K. Hebbar and Homi Bhabha. It was built in 1952. Managed by the Committee of Management, the entire cost of this mansion was donated by Cowasji Jehangir. This gallery is situated at Kala Ghoda, behind the Prince of Wales Museum, in South Mumbai near the Gateway of India, and has four exhibition halls. The gallery was designed by G.M.Bhuta for G.M. Bhuta and Associates</string>

    <string name="ngoma">NATIONAL GALLERY OF MODERN ART</string>
    <string name="ngoma_desc">National Gallery of Modern Art, Mumbai was opened to the public in 1996. It hosts various exhibitions and art collections of famous artists, sculptors and different civilisations. It is located near Regal Cinema in Colaba.</string>

    <!-- Restaurants -->
    <string name="oberoi">Oberoi Trident Towers</string>
    <string name="oberoi_desc">Room Amenities: The 287 elegantly appointed rooms and suites are equipped with a range of modern technologies including an LCD television, DVD player, iPod dock, electronic safe and waterproof television in the bathroom.\nHotel Facilities: The luxurious Oberoi Spa, open 24 hours a day, is great for Ayurveda or just a rejuvenating spa treatment. A luxury retail arcade, temperature-controlled outdoor pool, and fitness centre.The well-equipped 24-hour business centre caters to the diverse needs of corporate guests. Situated on the top floor of the hotel are the two conference rooms - the Jaipur Suite and the Udaipur Suite, which offer spectacular views.\nDining: Enter a world of gastronomic delight at the three in-house restaurants - Fenix (multi-cuisine), Vetro (Italian) and Ziya ( modern Indian). The Champagne Lounge, and The Oberoi Patisserie and Delicatessen are perfect places to enjoy fresh, healthy snacks, organic tea and coffee. Enjoy and unwind with an aperitif or nightcap while enjoying live music at the stylish The Eau Bar.Savour specially curated modern Indian delicacies in Ziya, or hand crafted sushi and Japanese sake in Fenix.</string>

    <string name="yauatcha">Yauatcha Mumbai</string>
    <string name="yauatcha_desc">If you are looking for good quality Chinese food and you are the sort of person who can live on dim sums then this is the restaurant for you. It is run by the same folks that handle Hakkasan, another popular Chinese eatery in Bandra West but here the focus is specifically on dim sums and their wide range of teas, almost 24 different varieties from around the world. Dim sum tends to be very under rated and usually restricted to a token few choices in the appetizer section on most menus but here the choice is plenty and the idea is to make a meal of it just like the Chinese do.</string>

    <string name="celini">Celini</string>
    <string name="celini_desc">Italian classics and a vast array of wines offered in an upscale, modern setting at the Grand Hyatt</string>

    <string name="btm">By the Mekong</string>
    <string name="btm_desc">Towering luxury hotel\'s elegant city view pan Asian restaurant on the 37th floor</string>

    <!-- Events -->
    <string name="gc">Ganesh Chaturthi </string>
    <string name="gc_desc">Ganesh Chaturthi (IAST: Gaṇēśa Chaturthī), also known as Vinayaka Chaturthi (Vināyaka Chaturthī) is the Hindu festival that reveres god Ganesha. A ten-day festival, it starts on the fourth day of Hindu luni-solar calendar month Bhadrapada, which typically falls in Gregorian months of August or September. The festival is marked with installation of Ganesha clay idols privately in homes, or publicly on elaborate pandals (temporary stage). Observations include chanting of Vedic hymns and Hindu texts such as Ganapati Upanishad, prayers and vrata (fasting). Offerings and prasada from the daily prayers, that is distributed from the pandal to the community, include sweets such as modaka believed to be a favorite of the elephant-headed deity. The festival ends on the tenth day after start, wherein the idol is carried in a public procession with music and group chanting, then immersed in nearby water body such as a river or ocean, thereafter the clay idol dissolves and Ganesha is believed to return to Mount Kailash to Parvati and Shiva.\nThe festival celebrates Lord Ganesha as the God of New Beginnings and the Remover of Obstacles as well as the god of wisdom and intelligence and is observed throughout India, especially in the states of Maharashtra, Goa, Telangana, Gujarat and Chhattisgarh,  and is usually celebrated privately at home in states of Karnataka, Tamil Nadu, Andhra Pradesh and Madhya Pradesh.[8] Ganesh Chaturthi is also observed in Nepal and by the Hindu diaspora elsewhere such as in the Trinidad, Suriname, Fiji, Mauritius , United States and in Europe.</string>

    <string name="md">MOOD INDIGO</string>
    <string name="md_desc">Mood Indigo, also known as MoodI or MI, is the annual cultural festival of the Indian Institute of Technology Bombay. It is an event usually held towards the end of December every year. The 2015 edition of Mood Indigo witnessed a footfall of more than 1,31,000 students from over 1650 colleges from across the country. Started in 1971 by a group of enthusiastic IITians, Mood Indigo,now in its 46th edition, has become the largest college cultural festival in the country. Over the years, MI has also attracted considerable media attention and numerous well-known sponsors.</string>

    <string name="holi">Holi</string>
    <string name="holi_desc">Holi  is a Hindu spring festival celebrated in the Indian subcontinent, also known as the "festival of colours".The festival signifies the victory of good over evil, the arrival of spring, end of winter, and for many a festive day to meet others, play and laugh, forget and forgive, and repair broken relationships. It is also celebrated as a thanksgiving for a good harvest.  It lasts for a night and a day, starting on the evening of the Purnima (Full Moon day) falling in the Vikram Samvat Hindu Calendar month of Phalguna, which falls somewhere between the end of February and the middle of March in the Gregorian calendar. The first evening is known as Holika Dahan or Chhoti Holi and the following day as Holi, Rangwali Holi, Dhuleti, Dhulandi, or Phagwah.\nHoli is an ancient Hindu religious festival which has become popular with non-Hindus in many parts of South Asia, as well as people of other communities outside Asia. In recent years the festival has spread to parts of Europe and North America as a spring celebration of love, frolic, and colours.\nHoli celebrations start on the night before Holi with a Holika Dahan where people gather, perform religious rituals in front of the bonfire, and pray that their internal evil be destroyed the way Holika, the sister of the demon king Hiranyakashipu, was killed in the fire. The next morning is celebrated as Rangwali Holi – a free-for-all festival of colours, where people smear each other with colours and drench each other. Water guns and water-filled balloons are also used to play and colour each other. Anyone and everyone is fair game, friend or stranger, rich or poor, man or woman, children and elders. The frolic and fight with colours occurs in the open streets, open parks, outside temples and buildings. Groups carry drums and other musical instruments, go from place to place, sing and dance. People visit family, friends and foes to throw coloured powders on each other, laugh and gossip, then share Holi delicacies, food and drinks.Some customary drinks include bhang (marijuana), which is intoxicating.</string>

    <string name="diwali">DIWALI</string>
    <string name="diwali_desc">Diwali or Deepavali is the Hindu festival of lights celebrated every year in autumn in the northern hemisphere (spring in southern hemisphere). It is an official holiday in Fiji, Guyana, India, Malaysia, Mauritius, Myanmar, Nepal, Singapore, Sri Lanka, Suriname, and Trinidad and Tobago. One of the most popular festivals of Hinduism, it spiritually signifies the victory of light over darkness, good over evil, knowledge over ignorance, and hope over despair. Its celebration includes millions of lights shining on housetops, outside doors and windows, around temples and other buildings in the communities and countries where it is observe. The festival preparations and rituals typically extend over a five-day period, but the main festival night of Diwali coincides with the dark night of the Hindu Lunisolar month Kartika in Bikram Sambat calendar (the month of Aippasi in Tamil Calendar), on the 15th of the month. In the Gregorian calendar, Diwali night falls between mid-October and mid-November.\nBefore Diwali night, people clean, renovate, and decorate their homes and offices. On Diwali night, people dress up in new clothes or their best outfits, light up diyas (lamps and candles) inside and outside their home, participate in family puja (prayers) typically to Lakshmi – the goddess of fertility and prosperity. After puja, fireworks follow, then a family feast including mithai (sweets), and an exchange of gifts between family members and close friends. Diwali also marks a major shopping period in nations where it is celebrated.\nThe name of festive days as well as the rituals of Diwali vary significantly among Hindus, based on the region of India. In many parts of India, the festivities start with Dhanteras (in northern and western part of India). Dhanteras is followed by Naraka Chaturdasi on second day, Diwali on the third day. Next day after After Diwali, this is Goverdhan pooja solemnised in Northern part of the country. On the same day, in some places, Diwali Padva is celebrated which is dedicated to wife–husband relationship. On the fourth day, festivities end with Bhai Dooj dedicated to sister–brother bond on the fifth day. Dhanteras usually falls eighteen days after Dussehra.\nOn the same night that Hindus celebrate Diwali, Jains celebrate a festival also called Diwali to mark the attainment of moksha by Mahavira, Sikhs celebrate Bandi Chhor Divas to mark the release of Guru Hargobind from a Mughal Empire prison, and Newar Buddhists, unlike the majority of Buddhists, celebrate Diwali by worshipping Lakshmi.</string>

</resources>
